# **Haseeb Shahid**

haseeb.shahid534@gmail.com +923144366017 52 Hassan Block, Nishter colony, Ferozpur road Lahore, Pakistan



With 6 years of software development experience, including a year as a Team Lead at a startup, I specialize in the MERN stack. My expertise extends to React.js, Express.js, Node.js, Angular, .NET, MongoDB, and SQL. I have a strong background in Agile methodologies, ensuring efficient processes and high-quality results in professional environments.

# **Work Experience**

# Staples Canada | Feb 2024 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

- Working as Full stack Developer to maintain and develop a large scale product.
- Coding of system components according to design specifications, corporate standards and best practices and solution design
- Implemented the detailed application design of the system provided by the application Architect.
- Participated in design and code walk-through for review and incorporate feedback into design and code artifacts

# MountSol | Jul 2022 - FEB 2024

Team Lead

- Helped local industry to build a team of professional developers.
- Client meetings, task assignment, implemented processes, training, mentorship.
- Defined architectures and ensured industrial approaches.

# Emerald Labs | Jul 2020 – Jun 2022

Full Stack Developer

- Helped US clients in bringing their ideas into reality using industrial standards.
- Designed and implemented Health care and accounting solutions.
- Digital healthcare solutions helped patients and agencies to operate remotely and reduced the cost of home care and cardiac rehab which helped a huge number of clients in fighting health challenges.
- Worked individually and across the team to find the best solution at minimal cost. Parted in team growth for expansion and training of junior resources

### **Logics Bay** | **MAY 2017 – OCT 2020**

Full Stack Developer

- Migrated an already implemented solution from AngularJS to Angular 8.
- Designed and implemented Managed Service Provider.
- ITBoost helped 1500 organizations in managing their companies and all the related information at one place through proper logs and third party integrations.
- Teamwork to manage the tasks efficiently in order to meet tight deadlines while maintaining the high quality standards.
- Designed and Implemented educational, accounting and delivery solutions.
- Learned the industrial standards and continued growing as an independent developer as well as a team player.

#### Education

### BS Information Technology | [2014 - 2018]

Punjab University college of Information Technology Lahore, Pakistan

# **Projects**

# Ajwa E-commerce

- o E-Commerce web for online shopping
- Shop, return, order management, stats, user management

#### **Tools & Technologies:**

Next.js, Postgres, Bootstrap 5, Redux, AWS

### La Quinta Resort

- Vacation and event planning on resorts
- Workspaces, tenant, sub-tenant management and switching for admin and client.
- Places, rooms, events, restaurants, categories and subcategories management

#### **Tools & Technologies:**

ReactJs, Node.js, MongoDB, Material Design, Redux, AWS

#### **School Finder**

- o MVP for finding nearby schools
- School management, parent profile and manage children, search nearby schools, admission and fee processing, ratings and reviews.

#### **Tools & Technologies:**

React Native, Google places, Firebase

#### Rameen San

- Automated restaurant ordering, preparation and accounts.
- QR scanner, menu, offers, deals, tracking, payment, settings and accounts management

#### **Tools and Technologies:**

ReactJs, PHP, MySQL, Material Design

### **PrognosUS**

- o Community health app for dementia patients
- Create a community based on dementia stage, determined by dynamic assessment, where they can discuss their challenges and get support from the community.
- o Patient management and recovery.

#### **Tools & Technologies:**

ReactJs, AWS Amplify, Twilio, Form.io, DynamoDB, Bootstrap, CI/CD

#### TN-Visa

- Automated process for US Visa application, for both individual and family
- Step by step guidance and verification for each user
- Dynamic forms, payment gateway, case handling, ACL

#### **Tools & Technologies:**

ReactJs, AWS Amplify, Form.io, Postgres, twilio, RoR, Stripe, Figma

#### **TaxTaker**

- Fintech app which helps to save upto \$0.5M each year in taxation.
- Client management, year wise records, third parties integrations, task base tracking - Admin can request for specific data by creating a unique link with required modules.

#### **Tools & Technologies:**

Angular, MySQL, RoR, AWS, Hubspot, Figma, Angular Material

#### Ucardia

- A management system which allows hospitals to track and maintain the Health of heart patients.
- Seamlessly track patient activity and health and keep motivated through streaks, achievements and daily goals.
- Patient community and health provider interaction via chat, audio and video calling

#### **Tools & Technologies:**

ReactJs, MySQL, Node.js, Express, Figma, twilio, GCP, REST API.

# **Identify**U

- AI based web app which helps in finding a happier, peaceful and meaningful life.
- Dynamic forms, user management, stats, reports and runtime assessments.

#### **Tools & Technologies:**

ReactJs, Postgres, twilio, ROR, Stripe, Figma

#### **TaxTaker**

- o Fintech app which helps to save upto \$0.5M each year in taxation.
- Client management, year wise records, third parties integrations, task base tracking - Admin can request for specific data by creating a unique link with required modules.

#### **Tools & Technologies:**

Angular, MySQL, RoR, AWS, Hubspot, Figma, Angular Material

#### Ucardia

- A management system which allows hospitals to track and maintain the Health of heart patients.
- Seamlessly track patient activity and health and keep motivated through streaks, achievements and daily goals.
- Patient community and health provider interaction via chat, audio and video calling

#### **Tools & Technologies:**

ReactJs, MySQL, Node.js, Express, Figma, twilio, GCP, REST API.

# CareSnap

- A platform for agencies to maintain their patients and health providers - COVID assessment and daily reporting to agencies.
- Hours logging, shift coverage and earning management

#### **Tools & Technologies:**

ReactJs, NodeJs, Express, MySQL, AWS, REST API, CI/CD